# Francisco Nogueira

# **Senior UX Designer**

Located in Berlin, Germany (+49) 1575 768 74 38 franciscoscn@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/franciscoscn/

Behance: https://www.behance.net/fscn/

Combining 11 years of experience in design, 3D art, and teaching to offer exceptionally polished digital experiences. Passionate about human centered design and understanding the needs of users and businesses in order to successfully problem solve and engage people.

#### **Skills**

- Human Centered Design
- User Research
- Journey Maps
- Personas
- Task Analysis
- Information Architecture
- Wireframing
- Prototyping
- · Usability Testing
- UI & Visual Design
- Agile Development
- Design Systems
- 3D Art & Motion Design
- 3D Visualization
- Basic HTML, CSS, JS

### **Design Tools**

- Sketch
- Figma
- InVision
- ProtoPie
- Miro
- Illustrator
- After Effects

#### **3D Tools**

- Maya
- 3ds Max
- Cinema 4D
- Blender
- Unreal Engine
- Unity

# Languages

- Portuguese (native)
- English (C2)
- German (B1)
- Spanish (B1)

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### **UX Designer**

Ergosign, GmbH / SEP 2021-PRESENT / BERLIN

Creating high level UX design and solving service design problems on a critical team for the world's biggest dental care supplier.

#### **3D Art Teacher**

WAVE AKADEMIE für Digitale Medien / JUN 2019-SEP 2021 / BERLIN

Designed the courses and lectures, and taught the foundations of 3D, visual arts, and design to the Game Design and 3D Art courses.

#### **3D & VFX Artist**

Boldbreed: agency for creatives / SEP 2017-SEP 2021 / BERLIN

Produced 3D and visual effects content for communication, TV, advertising, and architectural visualization projects.

#### **3D Artist**

PLAJER + FRANZ Studio / JUL 2016 – JUL 2017 / BERLIN

Created 3D visualizations of architecture, hospitality spaces, and interior design for luxury retail brands like Karl Lagerfeld and Chevrolet.

#### **3D & VFX Artist**

Jump Willy & Freelancer / OCT 2010-JUL 2016 / PORTO, PORTUGAL

Directed and produced 3D content for institutional spots, advertising, video games, music videos, fashion, medical, and architectural projects.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **UX Design Program**

CareerFoundry / FEB 2021-FEB 2022 / BERLIN

400+ hours of UX Design study and practice, covering design methodologies, research methods, information architecture, personas, prototypes, user testing, analytics, agile development and design systems.

# Master of Arts (MA), Computer Animation

Universidade Católica Portuguesa / 2008-2010 / PORTO, PORTUGAL

### Bachelor of Arts (BA), Communication & Multimedia

UTAD / 2005-2008 / VILA REAL, PORTUGAL